Guide to the Charlotte Cohen Collection Related to Gardening, 1950-2002 AIS.2005.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Charlotte Cohen Collection Related to Gardening
1950-2002
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Cohen, Charlotte
AIS.2005.05
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collection includes items from the 1970 Allegheny County Fair, Mellon Park, Squirrel Hill, and correspondence collected by Charlotte Cohen, all of which sheds light into Pittsburgh's gardening community during the 1950s-1970s.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection was assembled by Charlotte Cohen, the volunteer historian at Phipps Conservatory since the late 1980s. It presents a small snapshot of some of the Pittsburgh gardening community's activities and initiatives through the 1950s on into the 1970s. The first box deals primarily with the Allegheny County Fair, specifically in the year 1970. These files contain photographs from the site and details of a flower contest. There are also several folders labeled "Judges Awards" which are broken down by category according to the flowers grown.
File folder ten and eleven presents many articles and photographs of Mellon Park in downtown Pittsburgh from its opening in 1955. The final folder in the first box and first three folders in the second include additional photography of gardens and green space throughout Pittsburgh. The last three folders include a floral publication along with events to correspond with Pittsburgh's bicentennial celebration in 1958.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charlotte Cohen in 2005.
Previous Citation
Charlotte Cohen Collection Related to Gardening, 1950-2002, AIS.2005.05, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Allegheny County (Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); Environment; Mellon Square Park (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Women; Gardening -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Cohen, Charlotte; Phipps Conservatory
- Thirtieth Anniversary Allegheny County Fair Photographs, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allegheny County Fair Winner Lists, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- County Fair Floral Competition Rules and Regulations, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Allegheny County Fair Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Judges Awards: Annuals, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Judges Awards: Potted Plants, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Judges Awards: Dahlias, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Judges Awards: Roses and Delphiniums, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Judges Awards: Gladiolus, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mellon Square Park: Photos, Articles, and Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Rose Garden and Mellon Park Correspondence, 1950-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Floral Photography, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Pittsburgh Parks and Project Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Park Items for Squirrel Hill, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Giuseppe Moretti Magazine, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Pittsburgh Bicentennial, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photos and Prints of Phipps Conservatory, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)